Okay, so let's look at how we can implement this function.
حسناً، لننظر إل كيف يمكننا تطبيق هذه الدالة.
It accepts a parameter which is an array of strings called
إنها تستقبل معلمة عبارة عن مصفوفة من السلاسل تسمى names
'names' and returns a string which has the longest name found in that array.
وتُرجع سلسلة فيها أطول اسم موجود في تلك المصفوفة.
The first thing we want to do is we want to calculate
أول شيء علينا القيام به هو حساب
the length of our array and store it into a variable size,
طول المصفوفة وتخزينه في متغيّر اسمه size،
so that we know how many cells exist in this array;
بحيث نعرف عدد الخلايا الموجودة في هذه المصفوفة،
and then hence, build our loop based on that.
ثم نصمّم الحلقة بناءً على ذلك.
The second thing we want to do is initialize a variable called
الأمر الثاني الذي علينا فعله هو تعيين متغيّر اسمه longestName مثلاً،
And we want to initialize it to names of zero,
ونريد تعيين قيمته بالخلية صفر من المصفوفة names،
which is the first name in our array.
وهو أول اسم في مصفوفتنا.
Then, we want to create our loop that would start from one,
ثم نريد إنشاء الحلقة، وستبدأ من 1،
which is the very next name after that one,
وهو الاسم التالي بالضبط،
and it would keep going just before it reaches the size of the array.
وستستمر الحلقة على هذا المنوال حتى تتوقف قبل أن تصل إلى حجم المصفوفة.
The increment is just i++ as usual.
زيادة هي بالرمز ++i كالعادة.
Inside that loop, we want to compare the length of
أما داخل تلك الحلقة،
So we say, if names of i,
أي سنقول: if(names[i]
which is the string in that particular cell of the array at the position i;
وهي السلسلة الموجودة في تلك الخلية تحديداً من المصفوفة والواقعة في الموقع i،
we say if names of i.length,
فنقول: if(names[i].length()
so we're measuring the length of that particular string;
أي أننا نقيس طول تلك السلسلة تحديداً،
and we're comparing it to the longestName.length,
ونقارنها بقيمة longestName.length()
which should be storing the longest name we found so far.
والتي من المفترض أنها تخزن أطول اسم وجدناه حتى الآن.
So if that name dot length is actually larger than the longestName.length,
فإذا كانت قيمة if(names[i].length أكبر من قيمة longestName.length،
then we update the longest name to be that name.
فسنحدّث الاسم الأطول ليصبح هذا الاسم.
It's very similar to finding the smallest number in an array as well,
الأمر شبيه كثيراً بإيجاد العدد الأصغر في مصفوفة أيضاً،
except that we're comparing if it's greater than rather than smaller than.
باستثناء أننا هنا نقارن باستخدام إشارة "أكبر من" لا باستخدام إشارة "أصغر من".
After we're done with our loop,
بعد انتهاء الحلقة،
that means we've visited every single cell in the array and we're
سنكون قد مررنا على كل خلية في تلك المصفوفة
always updating longestName if we find something that's longer,
مع استمرار تحديث قيمة longestName كلما وجدنا اسماً أطول،
that means we can safely return longestName. There we go.
هذا يعني أنه يمكننا الآن عرض قيمة longestName ونحن مطمئنين. ها قد انتهينا.